<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Fun With Bits]]></title>
  <link href="http://funwithbits.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://funwithbits.net/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-22T13:43:31-02:00</updated>
  <id>http://funwithbits.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raphael S. Carvalho (a.k.a. utroz)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ready to Have Fun With Bits?!]]></title>
    <link href="http://funwithbits.net/blog/2017/01/21/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-21T18:07:34-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://funwithbits.net/blog/2017/01/21/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone. I&rsquo;m really glad that I finally launched this blog. Fun With Bits.</p>

<p>Special thanks goes to <a href="http://catonmat.net">Peteris Krumins</a> who shared some
invaluable insights about blogging.</p>

<p>TL;DR: Bla bla bla about who I am. In this blog, I&rsquo;ll talk about software
development techniques, low-level hacks, game development, kernel, among other
interesting topics I feel it&rsquo;s worth sharing with my readers.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t expect people to know me prior to reading my blog because I&rsquo;m almost a
fresh blood &ldquo;getting started&rdquo;. That being said, I&rsquo;m going to introduce myself.</p>

<p>I think that my father (unfortunately, he&rsquo;s no longer around us) is the main
reason behind my interest in computers. When I was about 10 years old, he
taught me how to use commands to interact with MS DOS. I remember the most
important commands were to edit texts, execute programs, and navigate through
the file system. I don&rsquo;t know how many times I messed up with the operating
system, making impossible to boot it. I had a lot of fun doing it though.
After that, I was able to create my own websites using HTML and CSS. I didn&rsquo;t
even know what programming actually was at that time. I was just curious and
wanted to do interesting things with my computer.</p>

<p>I actually started with programming after I got interested in creating my own
alternative server for a MMORPG called Tibia. Of course, I didn&rsquo;t create the
server, but the experience made me learn how to host a server, manage my
website and consequently a database which stored players' data, and also
how to write scripts using LUA programming language for custom systems,
like quests and spells.</p>

<p>At that time, I wasn&rsquo;t even thinking of computer science as a career. I was
just having fun with bits. Pun intended :-)
But I changed my mind and joined a local university for a computer science
degree. It helped me a lot because I wanted to be the best programmer among
my peers. I worked really hard. A friend of mine a.k.a. kov introduced me to
the open source world. He told me about the job opportunities I could get if
I started helping relevant open source projects out there. IIRC, Linux kernel
was the first open source project I contributed to. The change was to slightly
improve the PID allocation code. I will not lie. It was extremely hard to find
something to do, but the experience taught me a lot. I was really obsessed
with kernel. I often found myself whispering the word &lsquo;kernel&rsquo; while showing or
walking down the streets. I wanted to better understand how computers worked,
from boot to application initialization.</p>

<p>As I was gaining more experience, I contributed to other projects until I got
my first job opportunity at an israeli startup called Cloudius Systems.
It was working on creation of a project called <a href="http://osv.io">OSv</a>. In OSv, I
worked with file systems. Mostly on improving ZFS support. I&rsquo;m working for the
same company, but now on creation of a distributed database called
<a href="http://scylladb.com">ScyllaDB</a>.</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;m considerably better than myself of 5 years ago, but there&rsquo;s a long
way to go until I can say I&rsquo;m really good with computers.
By the time being, I&rsquo;ll keep repeating this ZEN poem to myself:
“To follow the path, look to the master, follow the master, walk with the
master, see through the master, become the master.”</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll do my best to share interesting stuff with all of you.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
